Inventory of the Archibald Woods Papers 1777-1893, 1783-1846
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- W[illiam] Croghan, Pittsburgh, [Pennsylvania] to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2143)
  Asks that servant to be given in exchange for land on Hog Run be ready to be picked up.
- Daniel [Cruger?] n.p., to [Archibald] Woods, n.p., n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2144)
  Send survey by John Scott.
- John Cunningham, n.p., to A[rchibald] Woods, n.p., n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2145)
  [?] Russell called on him for note against Samuel Hudson. There is judgment against Woods for costs.
- H. Finch, n.p., to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2146)
  He and [?] [Poerm?] will take land.
- S. Fleming, [Barnesville, Ohio] to A[rchibald] Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2147)
  Would like to rent farm.
- John Griffith, n.p. to A[rchibald] Woods, n.p., n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2148)
  Has declined doing anything with Smith. Two hundred and seventy dollars will cover amount.
- Sam[ue]l H. Guthrie, n.p., to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2149)
  Asks Woods to wait until October for money.
- Sam[ue]l Hand, Zanesville, [Ohio], to Archable [Archibald] Woods, Wheeling, Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia], n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2150)
  Unable to collect money for Woods.
- Hiram Haymond, Palatine Hill, to A[rchibald] Woods, n.p., n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2151)
  Wishes to borrow $500 from [North Western] Bank [of Virginia].
- John Haymond to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], n.d. (Folder 2152)
  Think election will be between Jackson and himself. Asks Woods to "personate" himself at the election. "Pray do not let the revolutionists out general you at a time when danger appears to be so near to hand..."
- And[re]w Howlett, n.p., to Archebild [Archibald] Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2153)
  Because of infirmness, he submits his resignation as commandant of Company.
- Chas. Jack, [Marietta, Ohio], to Archibald Woods, near Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], n.d., 1 page. Fragment. ALS. (Folder 2154)
  Questions about location of tract of land.
- Samuel P. Jones, to A[rchibald] Woods, Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia], n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2155)
  Bring deed. Will not fly from bargain.
- Knox & McKee, [Wheeling, Va Woods, n.p., n.d., 1 page. L. (Folder 2156)
  Wrote A.D. Clarke & requested him to Woods. Settle note to bank endorsed by R. Simms suit.
- Charles D. Knox, Louisville, [Kentucky.] to A[rchibald] Woods, President of N[orth] W[estern] B[ank] of Virginia,n.d., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 2157)
  Letter of resignation as bank director which Woods is to hold and use if he wishes.
- Isaac [Lest], n.p. to A[rchibald] Woods, n.p., n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2158)
  Let bearer have horses Woods is lending and send advertisement for horse Woods has lost.
- Letters, of Jasper Mallory, [Captina, Belmont County, Ohio] to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], n.d., 5 items. ALS. (Folder 2159)
  Concerns salt, sugar, wheat, rent due by Mallory, accounts due, and the rent of property at Captina.
- Mary McClure, n.p. to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2160)
  Asks Woods to help her brother David McClure to estimate value of land she wishes to sell.
- Rob[er]t McClure, n.p., to Archi[bal]d Woods, Richmond, [Virginia], n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2161)
  Requests for Woods to attend to by drawing money from Auditor of Pubic Accounts and bring back McClures' appointment as Inspector.
- Jno. McKee, n.p., to Knox & McKee, [Wheeling, Virginia] [West Virginia], n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2162)
  If he does not return in time, ask Col [Woods?] or Geo[rge] W[ashington] Wilson to remit money to Mr. Clark.
- R. McKee, n.p., to A[rchibald] Woods,[Wheeling, Virginia] [West Virginia], n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2163)
  Requests Woods to attend a Board meeting.
- John McLure, n.p., to [Archibald Woods?], n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2164)
  Horse sent back belongs to Alex[an]d[er] Caldwell.
- Geo[rge] Paull, n.p., to A[rchibald] Woods, Virginia, n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2165)
  Introduces [?] Jackson, a tanner who wishes to buy a lot.
- Sam[ue]l Purviance, n.d., to [?] Woods, n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2166)
  Questions about navigation of Elk and Ohio Rivers.
- W[illia]m Ridgely, West Liberty, Virginia [West Virginia] to Messrs. A[rchibald] Woods& W. Wilson, n.d., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 2167)
  Woods and Wilson are commissioners along with Johnathan [sic] Buckanon [sic], Josiah Morgan, David McClure to locate a road from Cummins's Mill to Wheeling.
- Eliza Spencer, "Harmony Hall," Pittsburgh, [Pennsylvania] to Arch[ibal]d Woods, n.p., n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2168)
  Asks that money due her be paid.
- Sam[uel] Sprigg, Richmond, [Virginia] to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 25 February [?]., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 2169)
  Power of attorney has been obtained from President of Literary Fund authorizing the subscription of $50,000 of [North Western Bank of Virginia] stock at Wellsburgh. Application will be made to Board of Directors to open books. Recommends it.
- James Stevenson, Alexandria, [Virginia] to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 25 January 18[?]., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2170)
  Asks Woods to come get his wheat.
- Ja[me]s H. Stout, n.p., to [Archibald] Woods,n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2171)
  Put a note in for Curtis & Co. for discount.
- Lucas Sullivant, [Washington,] to Archer [Archibald] Woods, near Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2172)
  Offers service in locating warrants.
- M.L. Todd, M.D., n.p., to [Archibald] Wood[s],n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2173)
  Under guard as a deserter. Defends himself.
- Rob[er]t W. Washington,[Wheeling, Virginia] [West Virginia] to A[rchibald]Woods,[Wheeling, Virginia] [West Virginia], n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2174)
  Mother has 100 bushels of wheat to grind.
- Alexa[nder] Williamson, n.p., to Archibald Woods, Ohio County, near Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2175)
  Desires to lease property.
- E[ugenius] M. Wilson, n.p., to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2176)
  Procured letter from Alpheus Willson for Woods to see concerning directors of North Western Bank of Virginia. Includes copy of ALS, of Alpheus P. Wilison to John Tyler concerning appointments of directors of North Western Bank of Virginia. 3 pages.
- Bill of complaint in lawsuit of Wilson vs. Woods in Botetourt County Court of Chancery, n.d., 1 page. Copy of D. (Folder 2177)
- R. C. Wood, n.p., to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2178)
  Requests Woods to write [?] Jacobs and bring patents with him.
- And[re]w Woods, n.p., to George Stucks, n.d., 1 page. Fragment. (Folder 2179)
- Archibald Woods, n.p., to [?], n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2180)
  Invitation. Glad [?] is Congressional candidate.
- Lt. Col. Com[mandan]t 4th Reg[imen]t, Archl[bal]d Woods, n.p., to Major Moses Shepherd, n.p., n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2181)
  Soldiers must bring public arms to batallion muster for inspection. "Whatever thoughts you or I had of resigning (as I most seriously had) it cannot it will not now do to resign until the storm is over;..."
- [Archibald Woods] to [?], n.d., 1 page. AL. (Folder 2182)
  Has received orders to march to Point Pleasant.
- [Archibald Woods] to [?], n.d., 1 page. AL. (Folder 2183)
  Concerning the location of a road (possibly the Cumberland Road.
- Memorandum of Instruction from [Archibald Woods] to Thomas Woods, n.d., 1 page. AM. (Folder 2184)
  To inquire regarding the payment to taxes. Woods is also to call on General Breckenridge.
- Memorandum of Archib[al]d Woods of land owned by Woods and Andrew Woods, n.d., 1 page. AM. (Folder 2185)
- Certificate of the recollection of [Archibald Woods] concerning masonry work on the turnpike road, n.d., 1 page. Copy of AD. (Folder 2186)
- Archi[bal]d Wood et al. to Governor [of Virginia], n.d., 2 pages. LS. (Folder 2187)
  Asks Governor to confer with President of United States to request protection from Indians. Also signed by Cha[rle]s Wells, John Dant, John Davis, Hez[ekiah] Davison, John Haymond, Corn[eliu]s Bogard, John Haddan, W[illia]m [Morrez?], W.H. Cavendish, and H. Caperton.
- [Archibald Woods] to Benj[ami]n Ruggles, Clairsville, [Ohio], n.d. (Folder 2188)
  Asks Ruggles to intervene in legislation.
- Appointment of A[rchibald] Woods as honorary member of Western Association for improvement of breed of horses, n.d., 1 page. DS. (Folder 2189)
  Signed by Jacob Lee.
- Notes concerning a lease to S[amuel] and H. L. Pickins, n.d., 1 page. (Folder 2190)
- Minutes of a meeting of Federalists from Monogalia, Ohio, Harrison, Randolph, Brooke and Woods convened at Morgantown signed by Archi[bal]d Woods, Chairman and P[hilip] Doddridge, Secretary, n.d., 1 page. MS. (Folder 2191)
- Archi[bal]d Woods, n.p. to W[illia]m Croghan, n.p., n.d., 1 page. Copy of ALS. (Folder 2192)
  Needs new deed from Croghan's father to be recorded in the County where the land is.
- [Archibald Woods], n.p. to Charles Hammond, n.p., n.d., 1 page. Copy of AL. (Folder 2193)
  Concerns lawsuit of J. Wilson v. Woods.
- [Archibald Woods] to P[hilip] Doddridge and Jno [John] Tyler,n.d., 1 page. ACy of AL. (Folder 2194)
  Concerns Bank of United States. If it is granted a charter, Woods suggests alterations and amendments to it.
- Agreement of Archi[bal]d Woods and Elijah Church to submit a dispute to the arbitration of Richard Simms and Joseph Marit, n.d., 1 page. DS. (Folder 2195)
- [Archibald Woods] to Levi Barber, Marietta, [Ohio], n.d., 1 page. AL. (Folder 2196)
  Asks Barber to send messenger to deliver legal notice to Stephen R. Wilson.
- Archi[bald] Woods, n.p., to James Smith, Capteena [Belmont County, Ohio], n.d., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 2197)
  Proposal to trade land.
- [Archibald Woods] to [?]. Concerns lawsuit of Wilson vs. Woods; the appointment of state directors to the Board of the North Western Bank of Virginia, n.d., 2 pages. Draft. AM. (Folder 2198)
  Includes [Archibald Woods] to [?]. Concerns establishment of post office at Capteena. 1 page. Draft. AM.
- Agreement between Archi[bal]d Woods and Elijah Woods to procure and locate military land, n.d., 1 page. Copy. AD. (Folder 2199)
  Elijah Woods failed on his part of agreement to explore or locate warrants.
- [Archibald Woods?] to G. Hancock, n. p., n.d., 2 pages. L. (Folder 2200)
  Wishes to make a settlement by purchasing slaves. Wants young ones not in habit of running away. "...those of a contrary disposition are however often the best slaves but situated as we are in this County between...Pencilvania [Pennsylvania] & Ohio...and where slavery is much ridiculed, any Negro of an interprising [enterprising] disposition and forward in their Manners are almost certain to go into one or the other states or down the Ohio;..."
- Notes of Archibald Woods concerning a conversation with [Henry] Clay about the National Road, n.d., 1 page. AMS. (Folder 2201)
- M. A. Woods, n.p., to Miss Julia Wilson, "Rose Lawn," [?], n.d., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 2202)
  Religious ideas.
- T. Woods, to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia, n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2203)
  Concerns sale of lots.
- T[homas] Woods, n.p., to Arch[ibal]d Woods, n.p., n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2204)
  Mr. Weaver declines to purchase house because wife wants to quit business of keeping a public house.
- Tho[ma]s Woods, to Alexander Reed, Washington, Pennsylvania, n.d. (Folder 2205)
  Asks for information from the city.
- [?] to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia, n.d., 2 pages. L. (Folder 2206)
  Mr. Hinds has agreed with M. Clark for oxen. Will accept your offer for his tract of land.
- List of claimants to land on L[ittle] Kanawha,n.d., 2 pages. M. (Folder 2207)
- Petition of [Archibald Woods?] to Congress requesting a military land grant on Ohio River, n.d., 1 page. AD. (Folder 2208)
  Includes plots on version of Maddison's or Jno Mitchel's land.
- Fragments of letter, wrappers, etc., n.d. (Folder 2209)
  Includes: Estimate of damages sustained by Archib[al]d Woods in consequence of lease given by Rich[ar]d Yates to James Fulton. Blank notes for North Western Bank of Virginia. Instructions for inquiring at Land Office in Kentucky. Instructions to take paper back to broker and get paper of Miami Exporting Company. Poem Lines supposed to be written at Genoa. Copy of deposition concerning a land dispute between Samuel Todd and the executors of Andrew Woods. Instructions for formation on parade ground and for inspection of sentinels by officer of the day. [ca. 1812]. [Alexander?] Caldwell to [Archibald] Wood[s]. Wants to borrow shovels. Parody of a candidates speech, Robert [Poage] to [Archibald Woods]. Petition to Virginia Governor to ask for protection for frontiers from Federal Government. Vote for governor of Pennsylvania in four counties. Formula for sheep-dip.
- Accounts and receipts. (Folder 2210-2233.)
- Surveys and plots of land, including plats of Woodsfield, Ohio, n.d. (Folder 2234.)
- Printed matter, business cards, clippings, n.d. (Folder 2235)
- Correspondence concerning the Poage family, 1891-1893. (Folder 2236)
  Correspondents include George W. Bailey, William C. P. Breckinridge, S. L. Brown, Mrs. S. T. Cook, T. Gallaher, Louisa A. Kemper, George A. Paull, A. J. Poag, C. C. Poage, Charles M. Poage, G. H. Poage, George B. Poage, J. C. Poage, M. Annie Poage, S. C. Poage, Thomas K. Poage, J. N. Powers, Margaret Sisson, Andrew W. Williamson, and Edgar Woods.